Mobile Suit
Rage on! Rage on! Rage on! Gundam!
Moeagare! Moeagare! Moeagare GANDAMU!
You must run forth!
Kimi yo hashire
If you are still burning with furious rage...
Mada ikari ni moeru toshi ga aru nara...
You must fight the towering foe!
Kyodai na teki o
Fight! Fight! Fight!
Uteyo! Uteyo! Uteyo!
Bring to bear the rage of justice, Gundam
Seigi no ikari o butsukero GANDAMU
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
Rise once more! Rise once more!
Yomigaeru! Yomigaeru!
Rise once more! Gundam!
Yomigaeru GANDAMU!
You must seize the power!
Kimi yo tsukame
Fly toward the galaxy, Gundam!
Ginga e mukatte tobeyo GANDAMU
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
The Gundam successfully fought off
Challia Bull's Braw Bro.
However, its control system was no longer
able to keep up with Amuro's will.
Amuro's reflexes and combat abilities
had continued to improve...
...making it evident that the Gundam's
performance was no longer good enough.
Modifications to the Gundam's
drive system began at once...
...but nobody could say whether
that would solve the problem at hand.
Lalah's Dilemma
Isn't it good that Amuro's getting stronger?
Then the Gundam will be stronger, too.
You're so dumb! The Gundam can't fight
unless it can keep up with Amuro!
Yeah, that's why everyone's so worried.
Go help out with dinner or something, kids!
Did you talk to them?
Yes.
They want us to go
to Solomon's technical headquarters.
Do the Federation Forces have a solution?
I can't imagine the Federation Forces
are that considerate.
Tell me, Mirai. I haven't noticed myself...
But have Amuro's combat skills
improved that much?
You can tell by watching his recent battles.
No. No, that's not what I'm talking about.
His intuition is so good...
isn't it like he's seeing the future?
You think so?
Fraw Bow, you sense it sometimes, right?
Yes, I do.
Amuro is different now...
Having said that, I don't believe
what Ms. Matilda said in the past...
...about Amuro being some kind of esper.
Human beings can't change themselves
so conveniently.
Of course not. Right, Fraw Bow?
Yes.
Mirai! We're entering Solomon.
Yes, sir.
I want all White Base mechanics
to step away from the Gundam!
We'll take over from this point on!
Hurry with the magnet coating!
What's going on here?
What? Who are you?
I'm Amuro Ray, the Gundam pilot.
I'm here because I read your report.
Don't blame me if this doesn't work.
After all, we've never had
a chance to test it properly.
What are you trying to do?!
I'm applying my theory
to make the Gundam move faster.
Are you sure that's possible?
They can't guarantee anything.
Mr. Bright!
He's Dr. Mosk Han.
A top electromagnetic engineer.
It's called a magnet coating.
They're making the Gundam's drive system
faster by wrapping it in electromagnetic fields.
See? It's sort of like oiling the joints.
Can they really do that?
There's no way I can answer that.
You'll have to ask the doctor himself.
I understand the concept, but...
I'm going to a strategy meeting.
We should take off shortly. Got that?
Y-Yes, sir!
It'll be fine.
Uh, yes...
I can't stand this.
Ditto.
Get a move on!
The operation has already begun!
Challia Bull has been defeated?
It was likely due to his inexperience.
Captain Char's reports said the Gundam
may not be tuned to a Newtype's abilities...
That Char. He's always guessing.
Pardon?
Nothing.
And what of Supreme Commander
Gihren's strategies?
Right! Our Granada fleet and A Baoa Qu
will form the front line...
...with the Solar Ray at the homeland...
The Solar Ray...?
Yes, that must be Gihren's doing.
The Granada base on the far side of the
moon, and this space fortress, A Baoa Qu...
The line linking them
is Zeon's final line of defense.
This is Mahal, the Principality of Zeon's
third closed-cylinder colony.
All right! Vessel 123, all set!
Thanks! Go ahead and take off!
You! And you call yourself a Zeon citizen?!
I've been separated from my granddaughter.
I was looking for her!
I guarantee you,
your granddaughter is on one of the ships.
But I won't know where her ship's headed!
It's within Zeon. You'll find her in no time.
Next group, hurry!
Get up! It's your group's turn to go now!
The mandatory evacuation of Mahal's
1.5 million residents...
...began four days ago.
It was obvious that this was part of a plan
to defend the homeland.
Panels of solar cells used at other colonies
were being brought here to Mahal.
The residents could only watch anxiously
as the preparations continued.
But Gihren...
Trying to evacuate a million civilians
only demonstrates...
...your incompetence as a soldier.
How dare you say that to my face.
Gihren!
I am the man who laid out
this nation's monarchical system.
And I can't support your militaristic...
Take a look.
I don't want to hear your plans.
For our Zeon homeland...
...the moon and A Baoa Qu
mark the final line of defense.
As such, the Earth Federation Forces
can invade us from these three routes.
Once they breach the line,
Zeon is exposed and helpless.
So we must attack the oncoming fleet
with the Solar Ray before they get here.
By using a colony for this system, we'll save
Zeon while also saving time and money.
What will you do, Gihren,
after winning at such cost?
I'd be honored if you'd sign your consent.
You're already started. Why ask me now?
Without Sovereign Degwin,
there is no Principality of Zeon.
And? What are you planning?
We've reduced the human population.
We'll maintain it at this level,
leaving only the superior races.
It's the only way humanity can hope
to achieve everlasting peace.
And it can only be done
by controlling humanity...
...through the dictatorship of the Zabi family.
Gihren. Are you familiar...
with Adolf Hitler?
Hitler...? The historical figure
from the middle era?
Yes. He was a dictator.
A man who failed to figure out
the rest of the world.
You seem to be following
in Hitler's footsteps.
Am I?
I established the Principality
as a means to quickly unite the Zeon people.
It was to make Zeon's ideals a reality.
But now...
This follower of Hitler
has created a dictatorship.
Together with Kycilia.
Yes.
Absolute democracy will only produce
weakness, as with the Federation.
Humanity will end up consuming itself.
Just as it's done in this war.
But I will be victorious.
See for yourself how Hitler's follower
fights this war.
I will take command at A Baoa Qu.
Don't forget that Hitler was defeated.
I've got it! One ship is a Magellan-class!
Three Salamis-class!
It's their minimum combat unit!
Send out mobile suits!
Captain Char, shall we send the Elmeth?!
Of course.
Don't give Lalah special treatment.
Lalah, you're not afraid, are you?
I-I'm fine, sir.
This'll be your first actual battle.
Cover the 2 Rick Doms from behind.
Yes, sir.
I'll head out shortly myself.
I'll do my best, Captain.
Any reinforcements from Granada?!
The Gwarib will be here in 5 or 6 minutes.
Hm. It looks like Lady Kycilia
has finally decided to take action...
J-missile!
Target the enemy Magellan-class!
Minus 0.2! Adjusting 2! Captain!
Good! R 0.3! 2! Left 0. 1!
Fire!
Aim second J-missile at the target!
Well done.
I'll head out in the Gelgoog.
Mulligan!
I'm leaving you in charge.
I believe you owe me a favor.
Be sure to do a good job.
Yes, sir!
I need you to give me 30 seconds
of covering fire after I've launched.
Yes, sir!
All right! 30 seconds of covering fire!
Don't hit our own mobile suits!
Good job, Mulligan.
C'mon, move it, Gelgoog!
Attack the portside Salamis!
I did it, Captain! I got them!
Those were the Elmeth's bits?
She fights like a veteran pilot already!
How can she do that,
when she's never fought before?!
All right. I'll get at least one more...!
The Doms aren't giving me backup?!
The Doms are retreating...!
Why are they moving behind me?
They're sending a first-time fighter
like me to the front?!
Do I have to fight on my own?
Without support, I can't concentrate!
Only one more, but...!
I can hear it again! It says la, la.
Source unknown!
I can't hit it!
Mobile Suit
Gundam
What's going on?
Buttsham!
You're supposed to be in the front!
That's crazy! With the Elmeth on our side,
there's no reason for us to fight up front.
Okay. I'll give it a try!
Lalah! Don't push yourself too hard!
I'll fire!
So I shouldn't rely
on my own shooting skills?
Captain...
Lalah. I'll cover you!
Captain!
As long as you're here...!
Hey! There it is again!
Next!
Well done, Lalah!
Captain!
Thank you so much for covering me.
Meanwhile...
...at Solomon, now the forward base
of the Earth Federation Forces...
...orders are being given
for the next operation.
This marks the beginning...
...of "Operation Star One,"
the plan to invade the Zeon homeland.
Each fleet will take its designated course...
...towards the target "star".
Though part of the 13th Autonomous Fleet,
which is meant to be at the forefront...
...the departure of the White Base is delayed.
I have confidence in my theory.
I believe I've successfully
eliminated all mechanical friction.
So in other words, there's no limit
to how quickly it can move?
Yes, in theory. However, the Gundam's
actual power is another matter.
That's true.
You're a lifesaver, Doctor.
If you survive, then you can thank me.
I just want you to find some way
to send me the data...
...from your next battle.
That's why it's best not to know
what people are really thinking.
You're absolutely right, Amuro Ray.
I'll put my faith in
your instincts with the Gundam.
Thank you very much.
Promise me you'll survive.
Okay!
So I can bring back your data, right?
Right! Precisely!
Go to full speed once we leave port.
Follow the forces ahead of us.
Roger!
The Elmeth could be more powerful
than your Gelgoog, Captain Char.
I'm surprised to hear that from
seasoned warriors like yourselves.
We witnessed the abilities of a Newtype
for the first time.
With that kind of power,
Ensign Lalah could single-handedly...
...wipe out an entire combat team
in a matter of minutes.
When we became aware of this...
it seemed ludicrous to risk our lives!
With a pilot as great as Ensign Lalah,
there's no need for us common humans!
Are you perhaps envious of Lalah?
Out of the question, sir!
Well, I can't completely rule it out.
But above all, we're truly amazed
by the power of a Newtype.
I'm prepared to face court-martial.
But all I ask is that you allow us
to fight behind the Elmeth when it heads out.
Can you handle it, Ensign?
I can understand the Lieutenant's feelings.
Then it's settled.
Lieutenant, are you satisfied?
Yes, Captain!
We'll reach the 13th Autonomous Fleet
in approximately 15 minutes!
Right! Attention, all hands!
Eat now while you still have time!
We'll be having combat rations
from now on!
Huh! So this junk isn't combat rations?
Could've fooled me!
I see.
This is amazing. But I...
Amuro, got a minute?
Sure!
Well, how is it?
It's great, but the faster movements
put an enormous strain on the parts.
It's very hard to find a good balance.
It'll be okay.
Have confidence, Amuro.
You really think so?
Of course. You're a Newtype, after all.
People usually tell me
I'm an old-fashioned type.
Sounds right. You're sentimental
and not at all far-out, Amuro.
When you phrase it like that
I don't feel particularly flattered.
Captain Char Aznable
and Ensign Lalah Sune, reporting.
The main forces of the carrier Dolos...
...have already been deployed
on the Granada-A Baoa Qu line.
Captain, you will join my raiding force
and take command.
Yes, ma'am.
I don't like that outfit.
Pardon?
Give the supply corps
the Ensign's uniform size.
The supply corps keep insisting
we don't win wars with our clothing.
Make them rush it in my name.
Her clothes are an eyesore.
So, how was her performance test?
Destroyed two Salamis ships
in her very first combat.
Lalah and the Elmeth
are a powerful combination.
Two ships? That's very impressive.
Yes.
The time seems right for the formation
of a special Newtype combat force.
I'd like to see the Elmeth in action.
That Dr. Mosk is really something.
No. It's more Amuro.
Huh?
The way he pilots the Gundam...
perhaps Newtypes do exist.
"Newtypes"?
"Newtypes"...
Mr. Bright! Amuro's...!
Hm? A fleet battle?
It's our rendezvous point!
The main fleet
must've encountered the enemy!
Who's the enemy?
Unable to confirm!
Prepare for fleet battle!
Gundam and all other units, take off!
The enemy force is huge!
We lost another ally...
It's calling me!
Wh-What is it?
I'm going for it!
One is Char...
And the other... Who is it?
Char!
Char! I have you now!
Captain!
It's all right to throw everything away now
ima ha ii no sa subete wo wasurete
What?! It's getting in my way!
All alone, I'm left as a corpse
hitori nokotta kizutsuita ore ga
In this battlezone
kono senjou de
I writhe in agony within the flames of hell
mogaki kurushimu jigoku no honoo
Captain! Pull back, it's dangerous!
Char!
You're in my way!
The Gundam!
The beam shines
beam kagayaku
It seems completely different
from yesterday!
In the flashback, I see his shadow
flashback ni yatsu no kage
Char! Char! Char!
I won't die alone! I call him again and again
hitori de shinu kayo yatsu mo yatsu mo yobu
Captain, move aside!
You're in the way!
Taking aim, Char is the target
nerai sadameru Char ga target
Char! Char! Char!
The Gundam...!
You hurt the Captain!
Char!
Captain!
Captain! Please eject now!
It's all right.
The Gelgoog won't explode from this.
But still...!
I'm going to cling onto the Elmeth!
Continue your attack!
I'm continuing. But...
But what? What is it?!
My head feels heavy.
Like something is pressing down on it.
What's this?!
You're a bad person.
What?
You're a bad person, bullying Char like this!
Who are you calling bad?!
The White Base made its rendezvous with
the 13th Autonomous Fleet flying ahead.
However, by this time, the fleet had
already lost three Salamis-class ships.
Two of these were destroyed by the Elmeth.
In total, Lalah had destroyed
four vessels in one day.
This was an unprecedented accomplishment.
But if Lalah's headaches have
something to do with the Gundam pilot...
...that could definitely complicate matters.
And now, the battlefield shifts
toward the far side of the moon.
The fierce battle between
the Gundam and the Elmeth...
...shows Amuro and Lalah a vision of
the destiny toward which they must move.
But the battlefield engulfs them,
then spreads to enormous proportions.
Lalah will perish.
Mobile Suit Gundam. Next episode...
A Cosmic Glow.
Next Time
A Cosmic Glow
Will you be able to survive?
Amuro, do not look back
The star shining far off in space...
Amuro, it's your homeland where you were born
Do you remember the days of your childhood?
The morning when you woke up in warmth?
Amuro, do not look back, Amuro...
A man must hide his tears, hide his tears
Only look to tomorrow, to tomorrow forever...